Remember...
牢记
You have early stage Alzheimer's.
你有早期的老年痴呆症
- Have you gone to a vacation or something? - No.
-你去度假了吗 -没有
- So Munir has never been alone?
-Munir从来没有一个人吗？-不
You forgot to give water to your cat.
你忘给猫喝水了
How does it feel to be the only woman
作为凶杀局唯一的女性员工感觉如何？
I chose you from 50 girls.
我从五十个女孩中选了你
How nice.
真好啊
Since I won't remember, I can do anything I want, is that so?
因为我不记得了，所以我可以做任何我想做的事情，是吗？
Exactly.
正是
Do you have farsighted glasses?
你有远视眼镜吗？
I MET A GIRL TODAY. HER NAME WAS NEVRA ELMAS.
我今天遇到了一个名字叫内华达·埃尔玛斯的女孩
Chief Inspector Tolga Yazgan. Who is this?
首席检查官Tolga Yazgan：这是谁？
I must have dialed the wrong number.
打错了吧
This is Mehmet Yurtgil's home, miss. Who were you calling?
这是Mehmet Yurtgil的家，小姐您找谁？
I am his daughter. I was calling my dad.
我是他的女儿，我打电话给我父亲
Did something happen to him? Hello?
他出什么事了吗？
Yes... I'm afraid so, miss.
是的，小姐
DO NOT CROSS POLICE LINE
不要越过警察线
Follow me.
跟我走
- Who did this, then? - I don't know.
-是谁干的？-我不知道
You?
您？
If you're hiding something, you'll be complicit. You know that?
如果你隐瞒了什么事情，你会变成同谋。知道吗？
I told you. I don't know him.
我告诉过你，我不认识他
Neither his wife, nor him.
也不认识他妻子
So be it.
就这样吧
Whoever killed him, must know you, then.
不管谁杀了他，凶手一定认识你，然后……
Think about it.
思考一下
Who is able to commit such a thing around you?
你身边谁能做出这种事情？
- Nobody. - How do you know?
-没人 -你怎么知道？
I know everybody.
我了解身边的人
None of them could do such a bad thing.
他们谁都做不出这种事情
This is murder.
这是谋杀
Me?
我？
For instance.
例如
You think I could do it?
你认为我能做到吗？
No.
没有
You know why you say no?
你知道为什么说不吗？
Because you're afraid to say yes.
因为你害怕说是
Why would I be afraid?
我为什么会害怕呢？
Because if you said yes, then I could...
因为如果你说是，那我可以……
Here, in the middle of this road,
在这条路上
just shoot and kill you.
把你杀掉
And nobody would really know.
没有人知道
You'd be terrified. Understand?
你会害怕的，明白吗？
All the evil in this world is done by people we don't really know.
这个世界上所有的邪恶都是我们不认识的人造成的
That's why the first thing we do when we wake up is...
这就是为什么我们醒来时要做的第一件事是……
To fool ourselves.
自欺欺人
So I'm asking again.
所以我再问一次
Who could have done such a thing?
谁能做出这样的事情？
I have no idea.
我不知道
Chief...
长官
Agah. Agah.
Agah. Agah.
Agah! Agah! Please!
Agah! Agah! 快停下！
Agah!
Agah!
Agah, what have you done?
Agah，你干嘛？
Here you go.
好了
What have you done?
你做了什么？
Take that out of the rent.
从租金中扣吧
What time is it?
几点了？
- Ten past one. - Good, there's time.
-1点10分 -好，还有时间
Sorry, Agah, how do you know Kurdish?
抱歉，Agah，您怎么会说库尔德语？
- Kurdish, why? - You just spoke it.
-库尔德语，为什么这么问？-你刚才说了
Sometimes she doesn't recall her own name.
有时候她甚至不记得自己的名字
Can't you see her?
你看不出来吗？
What could my mum tell you?
我妈妈能告诉你什么？
She dances well, I heard.
她跳舞跳的很好
- Didn't they have a caretaker? - Of course they had.
-他们没有保姆吗？-当然有
But my dad, bless him.
但是我爸
He was a difficult person.
他是一个很难相处的人
Whoever they hired left after three days.
不管雇佣什么人都坚持不了三天
The last one left a week ago.
一周前最后一个也走了
They were alone since.
自从那以后就只有他们俩
Do you have the details of the caretakers?
您有保姆的详细信息吗？
Yes. I have everything.
是的，我都有
We spoke all the time.
我们一直都有联系
I'll give the numbers.
我会把电话号码给你
Can we leave now?
我们现在可以离开了吗？
Sure. You've had quite a journey.
当然，您经历了艰难的一天
One last thing.
最后一件事
Anybody who'd want to kill your father?
有人想杀你父亲吗？
Any name comes to mind?
能想到谁吗？
Who'd want to kill him?
谁想杀了他？
Miss! Your father was a judge in criminal court.
小姐！你父亲是刑事法院的法官
He must have put somebody in prison.
他一定把某人送进了监狱
But he retired years ago.
但是他几年前退休了
- Since you're coming from Madrid... - Olé!
-自从您去马德里以来……  -Olé！
Mom!
妈妈！
Let me tell you this way:
这样说吧：
- Bullfighters fight until they retire. - Olé!
-斗牛士战斗到退休 -Olé！
Mom.
妈妈
- But bulls fight until they die. - Olé!
-但是公牛奋战到死 -Olé！
- Mom!
-Olé！-妈妈！
- Mom.
-Olé！-妈妈
MY CAR TAKES PETROL. NOT DIESEL!
我的车是用汽油的，不是柴油
All right, sir.
好了先生
- You fill it up? - Yes, I made it "full".
-加满吗？-是的，我加“满”了
- Petrol. - Yes.
-汽油-是
Good.
好
But I'll tell you something.
告诉你件事
You don't make something full.
你不能让某件东西“满”
It doesn't exist in any language.
它不存在于任何语言中
Don't use it again, okay?
不要再这样说了，好吗？
Better forget the word.
最好忘记这个词
Wouldn't that be awesome?
那不是很棒吗？
If we forget everything wrong,
如果我们忘记所有错误
and only remember the correct things?
只记得正确的事情？
But don't you worry.
但是你不用担心
There's a lot of wrong in here. For example...
这里有很多错误，例如……
I thought my daughter was happy, but she wasn't.
我以为女儿很幸福，但实际上并不是
- Sir, it's 200. - Huh?
-先生200 -嗯？
200. Your bill.
200，您的账单
Take that upstairs.
拿到楼上去
We've flown 20 hours, and the car ride tired me more.
我们已经飞了20个小时，坐车让我更累了
Why do you say that?
为什么这么说
You took the scenic route, like a cabbie.
您像开出租车一样沿着风景优美的路线
The usual route had rush hour.
常规路线这个时候会堵车
That's...
这……
That's why.
这就是为什么
You've been living here for years. How could you be confused?
您在这里住了多年了，怎么会感到困惑？
I wasn't confused.
我并不感到困惑
- You didn't eat anything. - I'm not hungry.
-你什么都没吃 -我不饿
Are you ill or something?
你生病了吗？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Dad, what the hell? I just left my bloody house.
爸，怎么回事，我刚刚离开了我自己的家
What do you mean, ill?
你什么意思，生病了？
Okay. Won't you go back?
好吧，不能回头了吗？
- Are you kicking us out? - Of course not...
-你要赶我们出去吗 -当然不是
Don't worry. We won't stay long.
别担心，我们不会待久
- I didn't say anything. - Isn't number eight empty anyway?
-我什么也没说 -八号房间不是空的吗？
We'll stay there.
我们会留在那里
I'll find myself a job.
我会找一份工作
I could pay rent, too. Okay?
我也可以付租金，好吗？
Dad...
爸
I'm saying that I took my child,
我是说我带着我的孩子，
I left my house and come here.
我离开家来到这里
You're asking me if I'm... I'm not going back!
你还问我能不能回头？
- Okay, don't. - I'm not!
-好的，不要 -不能了！
All right, don't go.
好啦，不要走
Never mind.
没关系
I can't take it anymore.
我受不了了
- I just can't. - I beg of you, Zuhal.
-我不能 -我求你了，Zuhal
Daddy!
爸爸！
Please, Zuhal. My baby.
拜托，Zuhal，我的宝贝
- What will I do now, daddy? - You'll make him sad, too.
-爸爸，我现在该怎么办？-你也会让你儿子也伤心的
But I just rented number eight.
但是有人刚租了八号房
He just moved in.
他刚搬进去
CRIMINAL COURTS OF PEACE
刑事和解
THE NEW JUDGE VISITED THE DISTRICT GOVERNOR
新法官访问地区总督
Speak with the lab yet?
跟实验室沟通了吗？
I did. They're working on it.
嗯，他们正在处理
I was just trying to see where he previously worked.
我想看看他以前在哪里工作
Maybe I could see something.
也许我能发现一些东西
They'll call after the autopsy. Don't go anywhere.
尸检后他们会打电话，不要离开
- Won't you go in? - Who am I?
-你不去吗？ -我是谁啊？
We have you, after all.
毕竟有你在呢
But leave the file on my desk so I'll teach you to read.
把文件放在我的桌子上，我会教你怎么看
Teach her to write, too.
也要教她写
Ever seen me half-ass something?
你见过我做事做一半的时候吗？
Of course I will.
我当然会
It's my job.
这是我的工作
True.
是哦
See, I can write.
我会写
Don't have to teach me that.
不用教我
I MET AN OAF TODAY. HIS NAME WAS FIRUZ.
我今天遇到一个笨蛋，他的名字叫FIRUZ
- Did he go to sleep? - Yeah.
-他睡觉了吗-是的
Is the bed all right?
床可以吗？
It is, it is but...
可以，但是
I wish it could be all right up here.
我希望这里一切都好
- Is that my Walkman? - Uh-huh.
-那是我的随身听吗？-恩
- Does it still work? - It does.
-还能用吗？-可以
Where's the TV, dad?
爸爸，电视在哪？
I gave it to someone who needed it.
我给了需要它的人
- Don't you watch it? - I watched forty years of it.
-你不看吗？-我看了四十年了
- Okay, good night then. - Good night, sweetie.
-好的，晚安 -晚安，亲爱的
- Zuhal. - What?
-Zuhal -什么？
Take the spare key in that bowl.
拿那个碗里的备用钥匙
I gave one to Deva, too.
也给Deva一个
Yes?
喂？
Okay.
好的
I'll be there in twenty minutes.
我二十分钟就到
Good luck with that.
祝你好运
DEAR DIARY
日记
I ONLY TRUST HER. BECAUSE NEVRA UNDERSTANDS ME.
我只相信她，因为Nevra了解我
Timur, are you in? It's me, Nevra.
Timur，你在吗？我是Nevra
I'm coming...
我来了
Welcome.
欢迎
We've spoken before, but never met in person.
我们之前在电话是沟通过，但从未没见过面
Yes, hi.
是的，嗨
Nobody has any respect to the people in here. They barge in.
没有人尊重这里的人，他们会直接闯进来
That's why I lock the door.
这就是我锁门的原因
I had something else to do. That's why I was late.
我还有其他事情要做，所以迟到了
You're just in time.
你来的刚刚好
I was on a break.
我刚才在休息
You'll get used to it.
你会习惯的
People get used to the dead.
人们习惯了死人
They can't harm anybody.
他们不能伤害任何人
Not anymore, I mean.
我是说不会再伤害了
The thing is to get used to the living.
要学着适应
That's the hard part.
那才是困难的部分
You want something to drink? I can make some coffee.
你要喝点什么吗我可以煮咖啡
If you're making some for yourself.
如果你也要喝的话……
Did he really have a label on his forehead with your name on it?
他的额头上曾贴有一个标有您名字的标签吗？
- Yeah. - A serial killer situation.
-是的-是连环杀手的风格
It is.
是的
But, difficult to find one in this country of course.
但是，在这个国家当然很难找到
There are no serial killers in Turkey.
土耳其没有连环杀手
There are people who go on a killing spree.
他们疯狂的杀人
Now...
好了……
The shot was in point-blank range.
这是近距离射击
Less than two or three meters.
两三米之内
No signs of a struggle.
没有挣扎的迹象
He's been dead for 96 hours at the most.
死亡时间不超过96个小时
There's one entry wound, 7.65.
伤口只有一处，7.65mm子弹
Any sugar or milk in your coffee?
咖啡加牛奶还是加糖？
Nope.
不用了
Hello?
喂？
Okay.
好的
I'll be there soon.
我很快就到
It was the lab. They found a match for the prints.
是实验室打来的，他们匹配到了指纹信息
Seriously? You found him then?
真的吗？你能找到他了吗？
Thanks for the coffee.
谢谢你的咖啡
See you later.
回头见
Your honor.
法官大人
When will you legalize this?
您什么时候可以将其合法化？
Can you reach the prosecutor in charge?
您可以联系到主管检察官吗？
We'll need a warrant of arrest.
我们需要逮捕令
I believe I'm getting the hang of this.
我确信我已经抓到凶手了
I really do.
真的
I wish Mebrure could see this.
我希望Mebrure能看到
We loved each other so.
我们彼此十分相爱
So many memories.
许多美好的回忆
My only hope
我唯一的希望
is to die before I forget them all.
是在我忘掉所有人之前就死了
But how would you know that? Right?
但是你怎么知道呢？
Don't tell me that you loved too.
不要告诉我你也爱过
Yours isn't love. It's rancor.
你的不是爱而是仇恨
You don't love with rancor.
你不会带着怨恨去爱
- Is that the man's home? - Yeah.
-这是凶手的家吗？-是的
- He's armed, of course. - Probably, yes.
-他有武器 -应该是的
We'll go in, pick him up, then leave.
我们进去抓到他，然后离开
Pity.
可怜
You wasted it all.
你都浪费了
Your wife obviously loved you so much.
你老婆很爱你
Moved heaven and earth to make a home for you.
竭尽全力为你打造一个家
You took her for granted.
你却把她当成理所当然
I forgive everything...
我可以原谅任何事
But I don't forgive anyone who takes his wife for granted.
但我不会原谅任何将妻子视为理所当然的人
I have to be frank. I'm sorry.
我必须坦率地说对不起
Don't look at me like that.
别这样看着我
I could have picked somebody else.
我本来可以选别人的
But you're very guilty.
但是你罪孽深重
And you weren't properly punished.
而且你也没有受到相应的惩罚
What's eight years?
什么八年？
"Unjust provocation...
“因表现良好……
Time off for good behavior." Mitigation after mitigation.
获得减刑” 减刑后又减刑
They could have given you a medal too.
他们应该给你一枚奖章
I've read the trial records.
我已经看过了庭审记录
They gave proper consideration
他们给予了适当的考虑
but they didn't deal proper retribution.
但他们没有进行适当的惩罚
Therefore...
因此
You're getting your real punishment in here.
你将在这里受到真正的惩罚
You know what your punishment is?
你知道你的惩罚是什么吗？
You'll be my murder weapon.
你将成为我杀人的武器
Good, isn't it?
很好，不是吗？
Clear. Perp is not in. We're moving out.
安全，罪犯不在这里，收队
We're going in. We'll conduct a search.
我们进去搜查
That's Salih.
那是Salih
He's a decent lorry driver.
他是个不错的卡车司机
He even helped us move,
他还帮我们搬过家
and Mebrure is extraordinarily fussy.
但Mebrure非常挑剔
You'll be killing Salih!
你将会把Salih杀掉
Come on.
来吧
Give me your finger.
手指伸出来
Don't be difficult, my back is aching up. Come on.
别难为人了，我的后背酸痛，快点
It was so easy the last time. Give me your finger.
上一次真的太容易了，手指伸出来
Look.
听好了
If you'll be nice,
如果你表现好
I'll handcuff you the other way. It'll be more comfortable. Deal?
我会用另一种方式给你戴手铐，那样会舒服很多，好吗？
Agreed? Come. Give me your finger.
同意吗？来吧，手指给我
Come on, give it to me.
来吧给我
You're mad at me.
你在生我的气
But anyone else would've cut it off.
但是如果换了别人会把你手指切掉的
We're done.
大功告成
Of course only serving a sentence wouldn't do.
当然，只服刑是不行的
You need rehabilitation.
你需要改过自新
What's a sentence good for without rehabilitation?
没有悔过，服刑有什么用呢？
Nothing.
没用
Everyone collects something.
每个人喜欢都收集东西
And this is my collection.
这是我的收藏
I have a lot more, but this is special for you.
我还有很多，但这些对你有特殊意义
Keep this between us...
别告诉别人……
I pinched these from case files, back in the day.
这些是我从案卷里偷来的
You look at them well,
你好好看看
and think of the nasty things that you've done.
想想你所做过的恶心事
Okay?
好吗？
All things packed away, Along with yourself.
所有的东西都收拾好，伴随着你自己
Memories are scattered, To the room, everywhere.
记忆零散，到房间，到处都是
The perfume I'm used to Is no longer there.
我习惯的香水不再存在
You.
你
Your smile has faded From the nooks of the house.
你的笑容从屋子的角落消失了
Loneliness is bitter Please don't leave me.
孤独很痛苦，请不要离开我
We have loved this Colorless world together.
我们一起爱过这个无色的世界
You.
你
My woman.
我的女人
Remember when In the street across.
记得在街对面
We have kissed For the first time in my life.
我们有生以来第一次亲吻
Locked in embrace One spring morning.
锁定拥抱一个春天的早晨
You.
你
The lights are off The house is under dark.
灯灭了屋子里一片漆黑
Our warm sunlit house Has now grown cold.
我们温暖的阳光下的房子现在变得寒冷
Nights go on forever I keep on weeping.
夜永远继续我不断哭泣
You.
您
My woman.
我的女人
- Oh dear! - Dad!
-天啊！-爸爸
So sorry, sweetie. I...
抱歉，亲爱的，我……
You're up? Come in.
你起来了吗
Of course I'm up. You knocked the door all night.
我当然起来了，你整晚都敲门
Zuhal! Deva speaks!
Zuhal！Deva说话了！
Deva spoke to me for the first time!
Deva第一次对我说话！
Good job, Deva! Good morning, Deva!
干得好，Deva！早上好，Deva！
- Good morning. - Enjoy your breakfast, Deva.
-早上好-享受早餐，Deva
Come sweetie. Everything's ready.
来吧亲爱的，一切都准备好了
I won't stay, daddy. I have to go out.
爸爸，我必须出去
There was this Onat in my old company.
我要去我以前的公司Onatin
I wrote to him yesterday about a job.
昨天我给他写了一封求职信
- You just arrived, sweetie. - Yes.
-你才刚到这，亲爱的-是的
But we have to settle down as soon as possible.
但是我们必须尽快安顿下来
I'll drop by Deva's school, too.
我还要去Deva的学校
I hope they don't give me a rough time, with it being mid-semester, and all.
我希望学校那边不要因为是期中阶段让我难堪
Sit down, have some tea. I'll make you coffee.
坐下喝茶，我煮咖啡给你
I'll get something later.
等一下我去拿
You'll have a good time, grandfather and grandson.
祖父和孙子，你们会玩得很开心的
Sure. I'll show Deva around.
当然，我会带他到处转转
May I have some bread, Deva?
我可以吃些面包吗，Deva？
You're free to be alone, if you want.
如果你愿意的话，可以一个人呆着
Actually, you're free to be alone.
其实，你可以一个人呆着
I slept like a log last night.
我昨晚睡得很香
Nevra.
Nevra.
Sorry, Chief. I dozed off.
抱歉，长官，我睡着了
We ID'd the perp and raided his house last night...
昨晚我们确认了嫌犯并且搜查了他的房子
Okay, okay. Calm down.
好的，好的，放松
I've heard everything.
我都听说了
Go home, get some sleep.
回家睡一下
Come back in the afternoon.
下午回来
But you had to inform Firuz last night.
但是你必须把昨晚的事告诉Firuz
- It all happened so quickly. - The damage is done.
-事情发生的太快了 -于事无补
You go home now, okay?
你现在回家吧，好吗？
- Good night. - Good morning.
-晚安-早上好
Agah?
Agah?
- Agah, how are you? - Thanks, Rustem. You?
-Agah，你好吗？-谢谢，Rustem，你怎么样？
Fine, can't complain. Who's the lad?
很好，知足了，这小伙子是谁？
My grandson. He's arrived yesterday with his mother.
我的孙子，他昨天和他妈妈一起来的
Joyous news. You know your grandfather?
好消息啊，你认识你的祖父吗？
He's a killer.
他是杀手
You've killed the instrument.
你已经把乐器弄死了
You stabbed the drum!
你刺了鼓！
But thanks. They were being obnoxiously loud.
但是谢谢你了，那鼓真的很烦人
We'll have some peace of mind.
这回我们安心了
See you later.
回头见
Okay then.
好吧
- You stabbed a drum? - What?
-你刺坏了鼓吗？-什么？
Oh, it's not a big deal.
哦，没什么大不了的
Could I drop you off somewhere?
需要我把你送到什么地方吗？
Nah, I can go myself.
不，我可以自己走
Okay.
好的
Have fun, then.
祝你玩得开心
You too.
你也是
- Okay, see you later. - Fine.
-好的，待会见-很好
Salih the lorry driver.
卡车司机Salih
I know what you like.
我知道你喜欢什么
I dropped in without an appointment, sorry.
我没有预约就来了，对不起
Sending your CV would have been fine,
简历发过来就好
but Onat specially requested.
但Onat特殊要求
You lived in Australia?
你住在澳大利亚吗？
Yes, four years in Sydney.
是的，在悉尼住了四年
We just came back.
我们刚回来
- Why the laugh? - I don't know.
-为什么笑？-我不知道
People kill to be there, everyone's trying to leave.
大家都很想去那里，每个人都想离开这
But you've come back.
但是你回来了
You were a former employee of ours?
你是我们以前的雇员吗？
Yes, but...
对，但是
I mean... I worked here. But things changed a lot.
我的意思是我曾在这里工作，但是情况发生了很大变化
You come to me every day like it's your job, and you leave a 100?
你每天都来找我，就像是你的工作一样，才给100？
Go away.
滚蛋
This room hasn't changed.
这个房间没变
Still the same.
还是一样
Congratulations.
恭喜啦
No one drops by Human Resources,
人力资源部无人问津，
but you seem to remember it well.
你记得很清楚
No, this was my room.
不，这是我的房间
And the chair's the same, too.
椅子也一样
That used to be my chair.
那曾经是我的椅子
This used to be another department?
这是其他部门的吗？
No.
没有
It was Human Resources.
是人力资源部
I was at your position.
我曾坐在你现在的位置
Really?
真的？
Miss...
小姐
Are you here to take my job away?
你是来接管我工作的吗？
No.
不是
I thought that maybe you'd need some help.
我以为你可能需要一些帮助
How could you forget about filling up?
你怎么可以忘记加油？
- Come in. - Doctor, I'm so sorry...
-进来 -医生，我很抱歉……
- Doctor, it's important. - Sir, excuse me.
-医生，这很重要 -先生，对不起
Agah, come in. Please, calm down.
Agah，请进来，冷静一下
We're okay.
没事的
I have to tell you.
我必须告诉你些事情
LADIES' ROOM
女厕所
Nevra.
Nevra.
If you pull anything like this again, I'll make you sorry. You hear me?
如果你再做这样的事，我会让你后悔的，你听到了吗？
If you have more of those threats, I'll stay in here.
如果你继续威胁我的话，我就不出去了
Huh?
?？
Shit!
见鬼！
MESSAGE FROM THE KILLER
杀手留下的信息
What will I do?
我该怎么办？
If I'm already forgetting such vital things...
如果我能够忘记了如此重要的事情
Should I change prescriptions, you think?
您认为我应该更改处方吗？
I forget to fill up sometimes.
我有时也会忘记加油
Don't be so hard on yourself.
不要对自己要求这么苛刻
No one can remember everything completely and without error.
没有人能完全无误地记住每件事
You'll run out of petrol or gas!
用完了汽油或者柴油，无所谓的
What's important is to stay calm.
重要的是要保持冷静
And to find a solution.
并找到解决方案
You can't let anything out of the ordinary get to you.
你不能让任何不寻常的事影响到你
Sometimes the best plan is to not have a plan.
有时最好的计划就是没有计划
Make your mind up.
做个决定
Do I have a plan, or not?
我到底要不要做计划？
Do. Do have your plan.
要做，继续做好你的计划
I'm telling you to make changes when necessary.
如果到了不用做计划的时候我会告诉你
I get it. I'm not that old.
我知道，我还不那么老
We're settled, then.
那就没问题了
So I don't need to have a plan all the time.
所以我不需要一直都有计划
No.
不用
Adapt yourself.
适应自己
If only we could plan everything in advance...
要是我们能提前计划一切就好了……
There's luck to be reckoned with.
运气也是不容忽视的
Sometimes you have to trust your luck,
有时候你必须相信自己的运气，
and sometimes you just have to accept it.
有时你只需要接受它
There's something else that's important.
还有一件很重要的事情
I used to work in the Silopi Court of Justice for three years.
我曾经在西罗皮法院工作了三年
I thought I forgot,
我以为我忘记了
but I didn't forget to speak Kurdish.
但我没有忘记说库尔德语
No ATMs... We've been looking all morning. Nothing!
没有自动取款机，我们找了一个上午都没找到
- We can't see the turn. - But everybody's seeing this.
-也没看到转弯 -但是大家都看到这个了
- How could this happen? - I've heard about it. I saw it.
-怎么会这样？-我听说了
- But that's how he works. - Who is he?
-但这就是他的工作方式 -他是谁？
That charlatan journalist, Ates Arbay.
那个卑鄙的记者Ates Arbay
But I'm not mad at him.
但是我没有生他的气
I'm not mad at him!
我没有生他的气！
I'm mad at the idiot...
我对那个白痴生气
I'm mad at the fool
我对那个傻瓜生气
that sells this piece for a handful of money!
那个用这条消息换了几百块钱的傻B！
They'll send an inspector, and then we'll see!
将会有一名检察官到这来，我们走着瞧！
That's what's going to happen.
那就是要发生的事
Don't we have any other footage?
我们没有其他镜头吗？
No, Chief.
没了，长官
I don't want Deva to lose a year.
我不想让Deva浪费这一年的时间
I see.
我懂
This relocation is already taking its toll on him.
这次搬家已经给他造成了很大影响
Of course.
当然
So what do you say?
您觉得怎么样呢？
You think something could be arranged? Could you take him?
您可以安排他来学校吗？
What do you say, headmaster? Could you enroll him?
校长您觉得怎样？能招他吗？
I remember Deva now.
我记得Deva
Such a sweet kid. Had excellent grades.
真是个好孩子
He used to play something, too. What was it, a guitar?
他以前弹什么乐器，是吉他吗？
- It was a violin. - Yes, it was.
-是小提琴 -是的
Does he still play?
他还在练琴吗？
No, I'm afraid not.
不了
He doesn't play anymore.
他不再练琴了
Who knows, maybe we'll have him pick it up again.
谁知道了，也许我们会让他再练起来
Will you enroll him, then?
那您愿意招他进来吗？
To be honest, we don't have a place at the school.
老实说，我们学校真的没有名额了
But I'll do an exception for your son.
但我会为你儿子破个例
- Thank you. - But...
-谢谢 -但是
The payment will be different this time.
学费金额会有所不同
Since you're here mid-year, you won't get the discount.
由于是期中入学，因此没有学费折扣
I trust that's not a problem?
我相信这应该不是问题吧？
- You have a cigarette? - No.
-你有烟吗？-不
You have money?
有钱吗？
No.
没有
How will you screw her, then?
那你要怎么泡她？
She's a straight up whore.
她是个妓女
And are you her pimp?
你给她拉皮条吗？
I could be.
我可以拉
Okay.
好吧
And who is your pimp?
谁给你拉皮条？
What did you say? I'll fuck you up.
你说什么？老子干死你！
Stop looking at me.
别看着我
Come here.
回来
Stop!
站住！
Come here!
回来！
Agah, don't waste your time. It's out of order again.
Agah，别浪费时间了
I spoke to the mechanic, but he'll come late. He was busy.
电梯又坏了，我给修理工打过电话，但他很忙，会很晚才来
I have the worst luck.
真倒霉
- Rustem. - Yes, sir.
-Rustem -什么事，先生
- Give me a number. - Are you playing the numbers?
-随便说个数字 -您在玩数字游戏吗？
- Just give me one. - If it wins, we're partners.
-随便说一个 -如果赢了，我们就是合作伙伴
- 39. - Has to be up to 27.
-39 -不得超过27
If it's above 27, it's not a lucky number, huh?
如果高于27，那不是一个幸运数字，对吧？
Okay then, 24.
那好，24
- No, 26. - Make your mind up.
-不，26 -想好再说
In that case...
这样的话……
- Who am I speaking to? - I'm from the newspaper Simdi.
-你是谁？-我来自西姆迪报纸
Ates Arbay. How do you do, Nevra?
我是Ates Arbay，你好吗，Nevra？
Where did you find this number?
您在哪里找到这个号码？
I know you're angry, but...
我知道你很生气，但是……
Why'd you want to have an interview with me?
你为什么要采访我？
- They asked me everything. - Yes.
-他们已经问过所有问题了 -是的
I know they did, but...
我知道他们问过，但是
they didn't ask you the right questions.
他们没有问你正确的问题
What is that gift you have for me that'll be so useful?
那这次采访对我有什么好处呢？
Some information that exists in the outer space.
一些存在于外太空的信息
But you can't have it without an interview.
但是不接受采访就不能给你
I'll be the judge of that.
我来评估一下
I'll have to see what you have.
我要看看你到底有什么消息
And we'll see what we can do.
看看我们能做什么
Let's meet. Be at Isyan Sanayi after 10:30, tonight.
今晚10:30我们在Isyan Sanayi见面
Isyan Sanayi?
Isyan Sanayi？
- Deva? - It's me, mom.
-Deva？-是我，妈妈
- I... drank a bit. - I know.
-我喝了一点酒 -我知道
Don't tell your father.
不要告诉你父亲
Okay, go to sleep.
好，睡吧
Okay. Just, don't tell him.
好吗，不要告诉他
Don't say that I drank.
不要说我喝酒了
Don't tell him, okay sweetie?
不要告诉他，好吗亲爱的？
What are you doing?
你怎么开车的？
What is this? Do you want to run me over?
你想撞死我吗？
Hey.
嘿
- You were going to hit me. - Don't get mad.
-你差点撞到我 -别生气
I'm out.
我不行了
Goodness.
天意啊
- Do you like the music? - You're wasting your time.
-你喜欢音乐吗？-你在浪费时间
There's no such thing as 'DJ music'. Never will be.
没有所谓的“DJ音乐”，永远不会有
Don't tell anybody.
别跟别人说这句话
Who leaked the news, Ates?
谁泄漏了消息，Ates？
I'll always remember this first time you said my name.
我会永远记得你第一次叫我的名字
In a moment you asked me something impossible.
你问了一个我不可能回答的问题
Don't do it.
不要这样
Can I have my gift now?
可以把消息告诉我了吗？
I don't know. Can you?
我不知道，可以吗？
First the firewater.
先喝酒吧
- What do you pay for a gram? - What?
-多少钱一克？-什么？
Cocaine, I mean. How much do you pay?
可卡因，你要付多少钱？
They're overcharging you, I bet.
我敢打赌他们对你要价很高
Don't worry.
不用担心
You're just an information in an outer space.
你只是外太空的一个信息
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
You're just a number in a dealer's mobile phone. See?
您只是经销商手机中的一个号码，懂吗？
Is there a computer I could use?
这里有电脑吗？
You could work here without interruption.
你可以在这工作，不会有人来打扰你
I have to be back on duty.
我要回去工作了
Okay, thanks.
好的，谢谢
Nevra.
Nevra.
- Will I be in trouble? - You will.
-我会有麻烦吗？-有的
If there's a dealer like that somewhere, you will.
如果这里有毒贩的话，会有的
Glad to meet you, Nevra.
很高兴认识你，Nevra
So am I.
我也是
- Are we recording right now? - Yes, we are.
-我们现在在录音吗？-是的
- You'll give me a copy, right? - I said okay.
-副本会给我一份，对吧 -可以
I'll read you a list. The courthouse at Caldıran has burnt down.
我给你看一张清单，Caldıran法院大楼已经被烧毁
So did the one at Sefilpınar.
Sefilpınar法院也是如此
So did the one at Kambura.
还有Kambura法院
But you tell me you had nothing to do with them.
但是你跟我说这些事情都与你无关
No. How could I have the time for all of that?
不，我怎么有时间做所有这些事情？
Some other brothers must have taken care of them.
一定有别人在做这些事
How did you begin?
你是如何开始的？
There was this man, and he had a file in the courthouse.
有这个人，他在法庭上有一个档案。
But it's all slander.
但这一切都是诽谤
They made up all the accusations.
他们捏造了所有的指控
And I couldn't stand for any injustice like that.
我不能忍受这样的不公正
I'm a bailiff there, as you know.
你知道，我是那里的法警
I burned the whole thing down.
我把所有东西都烧掉了
So that justice prevails in the end, you know?
正义最终会占上风的，你明白吗？
Oh, man.
天啊
Oh, man!
天啊！
Why did you shoot me, man?
你为什么要杀我？
What did I do to you?
我对你做了什么？
You haven't changed at all, Naimhan.
你根本没变Naimhan
Not at all.
一点也没变
You used to be like this.
你以前也是这样
Always drunk.
总是喝醉
Aren't you afraid of what you'll do to your liver?
你就一点都不担心你的肝脏吗？
You wouldn't live long, anyway.
反正你不会长寿
You would live a bit longer, I suppose.
你应该活得更久一点
It wasn't your day.
今天不是你的日子
But so it goes.
但情况就是这样了
I ran out of petrol.
我没汽油了
I forgot to fill up the tank.
我忘了加满油箱
And you suddenly appeared.
然后你突然出现
I wasn't expecting it at all.
我完全没想到
But the doctor said so.
但是医生就是这样说的
Luck really does have to be reckoned with.
运气确实不容小觑
It's hard to follow people.
跟踪别人很难
Very hard.
很难
Pursue them all day,
整日追逐他们
wait outside their place.
在他们的房子外面等
What do they do, where do they go?
他们做什么，他们去哪里？
When do they go to sleep, when do they wake up?
他们什么时候睡觉，什么时候醒？
It's like having a job.
就像工作
Really.
真的
Man.
老哥
Where do you know me from?
你从哪认识我的？
Where did we meet?
我们在哪见过面吗？
Where are you from?
你是哪里人？
Kambura.
Kambura
And that's where I know you from.
那就是我认识你的地方
Don't do it, man...
别这样
I beg you, don't, man.
我求求你，别杀我
I'm not doing anything, Naimhan.
我什么都没做，Naimhan
I haven't done anything.
我什么都没做
You did it.
是你做了
You and them.
你和他们
All of you.
你们所有人
You shouldn't have.
你不该做的
I ONLY TRUST HER. BECAUSE NEVRA UNDERSTANDS ME.
我只相信她，因为Nevra了解我